Diane Di Prima Papers
Diane Di Prima Papers
1948-1971
Di Prima, Diane.
2.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American poet, author, and editor. Correspondence (1960-1971); diaries, playscripts and miscellaneous writings (1948-1966); and original manuscripts by others (Paul Blackburn, Robert Creeley, Ed Dorn, Kirby Doyle, Robert Duncan, Anselm Hollo, Steve Jonas, LeRoi Jones, Allan Kaprow, Kenneth Koch, Joseph LeSueur, Ron Loewinsohn, Clive Matson, David Meltzer, Frank O'Hara, Charles Olson, Stuart Perkoff, Gary Snyder, Norman Solomon, Gilbert Sorrentino, A.B. Spellman, Mike Strong, James Waring, Philip Whalen, Jonathan Williams) submitted for publication in The floating bear.
148943
Biographical History
Diane di Prima, poet, editor and teacher, was born August 6, 1934, in New York City, the daughter of Francis and Emma (Mallozzi) di Prima. She attended Swarthmore College briefly in 1951-1952.
In the late 1950's and early 1960's Diane di Prima became a member of a group of New York poets and writers, frequently known as the "Beats," who were centered in Greenwich Village. There she wrote and published several volumes of verse, and helped to found the American Theatre for Poets. She was co-editor of a literary newsletter, The Floating Bear, with LeRoi Jones (Imamu Amiri Baraka) during 1961-1962, and became the sole editor from 1963 to 1968. She was also the associate editor for Signal Magazine (1963-1065) and contributing editor of Kulchur magazine. She was publisher and printer of her own small-scale publishing houses, The Poets Press (1963-1969) and Eidolon Editions (1972-1976) and taught at Naropa Institute School of Poetics, New College of California, California College of Arts and Crafts, San Francisco Art Institute, and California Institute of Integral Studies.
In addition to founding the American Theatre for Poets, di Prima was the director and co-founder of the New York Poets Theatre (1961-1965) and the San Francisco Institute of Magical and Healing Arts (1983-1990), and founder of the Poets Institute.
Her numerous books include more than thirty collections of poetry as well as plays, short stories, novels, non-fiction, translations, and an autobiographical novel, The Calculus of Variation (1966). She has twice received grants from the National Endowment for the Arts (1973, 1979) and her work has been translated into over twenty languages.
Diane di Prima was married twice, first to actor/director Alan S. Marlowe 1962-1969) and then to poet Grant Fisher (1972-1976). She has five children: Jeanne (b. 1957), Dominique (b. 1962), Alexander (b. 1963), Tara (b. 1967) and Rudra (b. 1970).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Diane di Prima Papers comprise Correspondence, Writings in manuscript and printed form, Manuscripts by other authors, Miscellaneous items, and a file of The Floating Bear newsletter. The papers, which date from 1948 to 1971, are arranged in six archival boxes.
Correspondence (boxes 1-2) dates from 1960 to 1971 and is arranged chronololgically. Incoming and outgoing letters are interfiled, but the bulk of the correspondence is addressed to Diane di Prima. Her correspondents include John Ashbery, Lawrence Ferlinghetti, Allen Ginsberg, Denise Levertov, Walter Lowenfels, Charles Olson, Kenneth Patchen, Louis Zukofsky, and other persons notable in contemporary American literature. There are 98 letters, 1969-1971, from Alan Marlowe and 18 letters from Michael McClure. Some of the letters (including those from "Miles Campion," Edwin Denby, Diane Wakoski, "Anton Webern," and John Wieners) were published in The Floating Bear. A complete name index of the letters is appended to this inventory, and a chronological shelf list of the letters is available in the Manuscripts Division.
Manuscripts submitted to The Floating Bear and copies of the published newsletter itself are arranged in box 3. Of the 37 newsletters that were published, the first 35, 1961-1968, are present in the papers. The 86 manuscripts are submission copies of articles, poems, and reviews, arranged alphabetically by the authors' names. Prominent among the authors are Robert Creeley, LeRoi Jones, Kenneth Koch, Frank O'Hara, and Gary Snyder. Details on individual manuscripts appear in the accompanying shelf list; standard abbreviations indicate the physical form of the manuscripts, and dates are listed in the shelf list when they appear on the manuscripts. The number of the newsletter in which the manuscripts appeared is marked on most of them. All manuscripts of Diane di Prima are isolated in the next section, Writings.
Other Floating Bear records are reported at Indiana University.
Writings of Diane di Prima in manuscript and printed form (boxes 3-6) date from 1948 to 1968 and have been organized first by type and then alphabetically by title. These include a diary, nine notebook volumes, four manuscript plays, four reels of recording-tape readings, manuscripts of three groups of collected verse, and two folders of miscellaneous verse. The physical form of the writings is indicated by standard abbreviations.
A group of Miscellaneous material closes the papers in box 6. There is one folder of material on the American Theatre for Poets. Other items relate to the editing of The Floating Bear.
Purchases, 1963, 1968-1971
Subject and Genre Headings
Women Authors; Radicalism; Literature -- American Poetry; Literature -- American Fiction; Allen, Donald Merriam, 1912-; Ashbery, John, 1927-; Baraka, Amiri, 1934-2014.; Bergé, Carol, 1928-2006.; Berkson, Bill.; Berman, Wallace, 1926-1976.; Bissett, Bill, 1939-; Blackburn, Paul.; Brilliant, Alan.; Codrescu, Andrei, 1946-; Corman, Cid.; Creeley, Robert, 1926-2005.; Cruz, Victor Hernández, 1949-; Dawson, Fielding, 1930-2002.; De Loach, Allen.; Denby, Edwin, 1903-1983.; Di Prima, Diane.; Dorn, Edward.; Doyle, Kirby.; Doyle, Mike, 1928-; Duncan, Robert Edward, 1919-1988.; Eigner, Larry, 1927-1996.; Ferlinghetti, Lawrence.; Fraser, Kathleen.; Gadd, Maxine.; Gervais, Charles Henry, 1946-; Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997.; Girodias, Maurice.; Guest, Barbara.; Henderson, David.; Hollo, Anselm.; Jonas, Stephen.; Jordan, Fred.; Kaprow, Allan.; Kelly, Robert.; Knox, Hugh.; Koch, Kenneth, 1925-2002.; Kupferberg, Tuli.; Lake, Larry.; Lansing, Gerrit.; Laughlin, James, 1914-1997.; LeSueur, Joe.; Levertov, Denise, 1923-1997.; Loewinsohn, Ron.; Lowenfels, Walter, 1897-1976.; McClure, Michael.; Malanga, Gerard.; Marlowe, Alan.; Matson, Clive, 1941-; Meltzer, David.; Merwin, W. S. (William Stanley), 1927-; Morris, James Ryan, 1933-; Motherwell, Robert.; O'Hara, Frank, 1926-1966.; Olson, Charles, 1910-1970.; Patchen, Kenneth, 1911-1972.; Perkins, Michael.; Perkoff, Stuart Z.; Reed, Sweeney.; Rexroth, Kenneth, 1905-1982.; Rumaker, Michael, 1932-; Snyder, Gary.; Solomon, Norman.; Sorrentino, Gilbert.; Soyer, Raphael, 1899-1987.; Spellman, A. B., 1935-; Strong, Mike.; Vas Dias, Robert.; Wakoski, Diane.; Waldman, Anne, 1945-; Waring, James, 1922-1975.; Whalen, Philip.; Wieners, John, 1934-2002.; Williams, Jonathan, 1929-2008.; Zukofsky, Louis, 1904-1978.; Floating bear.; American literature -- 20th century.; American literature -- Women authors.; American poetry -- 20th century.; Bohemianism -- United States.; Italian Americans.; Literature, Experimental.; Periodical editors -- United States.; Periodicals Publishing -- United States.; Women authors, American.; Women poets, American.; Correspondence.; Diaries.; Manuscripts for publication.; Scripts (documents); Authors.; Editors.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - 1960-1963, 1965-1970 Mar-Jun, 21 folders (Box 1)
  - 1970 Jul-1971 Jun, 11 folders (Box 2)
  - Undated, arranged alphabetically by sender (Box 2)
  - no year, arranged by month and day (Box 2)
  - Envelopes not matched with letters
    - 1961-1969, 19 items (Box 2)
    - 1970-1971, 23 items (Box 2)
    - Undated, 13 items (Box 2)
- The Floating Bear
  - The Floating Bear newsletter, 1961-1968; Issues #1-35; 35 folders (Box 3)
- Manuscripts by others
  - Baker, Richard, "Beer", July 1961; ts poem signed, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Baker, Richard, "Struggle", June 1961; ts poem signed, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Blackburn, Paul, "Collecting the mail", ts, 2 pp. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Brecht, George, "Statement for James Goldsworthy", 7/11/60; typescript carbon, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Creeley, Robert, "The skeleton", ts poem, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dorn, Ed, "In my youth I was a tireless dancer", ts poem, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dorn, Ed, "Nose from newswhere", ts signed, 3 pp. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dorn, Ed,"The poet lectures famous potatoes", anno. ts poem, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dorn, Ed, "The song is ended", ts poem, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dorn, Ed, "Time blonde", ts poem, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dorn, Ed, "A wild blue,yonder", ts poem, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Doyle, Kirby, "Moon poem", typescript carbon poem, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Duncan, Robert, "Night scenes", ts poem, 3 pp. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Elmslie, Kenward, Review of dance works by Yvonne Rainer and Fred Herko, ts, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - F[ ], A.M., "'The automobile graveyard' by Arrabel", ts, 2 pp. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Feldman, Morton, letter to the editor of Floating Bear., 1962 Oct 17; als (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Hollo, Anselm, "Bertolt Brecht, A letter to his fascist friend Arnolt Bronnen in the summer of 1923", ts, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Johnson, Ray, untitled review of Claes Oldenburg happening., ts signed, 1p. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Jonas, Steve, "Green", 1958; ts poem, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Jonas, Steve, "Reply to Koenig's (Nouvelle Vague) in the 'Bear' 6", 1960; ts poem, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Jonas, Steve, "Sub voce", 1961; ts poem, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Jones, LeRoi, ("Frank Buck") "Consumer's guide", ts, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Jones, LeRoi, "Footnote to a pretentious book", ts poem, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Jones, LeRoi, "The politics of rich painters", ts poem, 2 pp. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Jones, LeRoi, ("John King") "Rejoinder: Concerning the reviews by Miss Zazeela and Mr. Marlowe in F.B. 16", ts, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Kaprow, Allan, "The construction of Boston", anno. holo. signed, 9 pp., with a covering letter to Alan [Marlowe] dated May 20, [1962] (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Katz, Micheal, "4 short stories for Passover", and postmarked 1963 Apr 11; four typed cards in an envelope addressed to William Linich (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Koch, Kenneth, "At the railway station", anno. ts poem, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Koch, Kenneth, "The building of Florence", anno. ts signed with initials, 3 pp. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Koch, Kenneth, "Chiarascuro", ts poem signed, 1 p. On the same page is the ts poem "Religiously" (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Koch, Kenneth, "Dostoevski's The Gambler", ts poem signed, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Koch, Kenneth, "Heanorupeatomos", ts poem signed, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Koch, Kenneth, "Mateeyanah", ts poem signed, 1 p. On the same page are the ts poems "Wahego" and "In harmonium" (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Koch, Kenneth, "The return of Yellowmay", anno. ts poem signed with initials, 3 pp. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Koch, Kenneth, "The revolt of the giant animals", ts poem signed with initials, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Koch, Kenneth, "Trieste e una donna", ts poem signed, 1 p. On the same page are the ts poems "Morro rock" and "Schweitzerreich" (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Koch, Kenneth, "An X ray of Utah", ts poem signed, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Krim, Seymour, letter to the editor, 1962 Feb 26; tls (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Landers, Dale, "Of a growth of ", ts poem, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - LeSueur, Joseph, "Random thoughts about recent plays, on and off Broadway", anno. typescript, 3 pp. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - LeSueur, Joseph, "Rotten apples", anno. typescript, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Lima, Frank, "Pudgy", mimeographed typescript, 2 pp. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Loewinsohn, Ron, "Coda: As far as they pass", anno. typescript, 2 pp. On the same sheet are the ts poems "Corky stupid" and "The footlights" (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Loewinsohn, Ron, "The world of the lie", 1959-1960; ts poem, 1 p. Attached are the ts poems "The mendacity of windows," 1 p., 12/59; "The mendacity of radio," 1 p., 3/31/60; and "The mendacity of sculpture," 1 p., 3/31/60 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - McNaughton, Ferencz, "May meeting with C. Coy", ts, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Matson, Clive, "Mainline to the heart", anno. typescript, 23 pp., inscribed "For Diane & Alan from Clive Matson" One copy of the Poets Press, 1966 edition is enclosed in the folder. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Meltzer, David, "Poem to H.P.Lovecraft", ts poem, 2 pp. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Meltzer, David, "The struggle/Poems for the Muse", ts poem, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Meltzer, David, "Heroes: 7/ The comics", ts poem, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Nalota, Louise, "Tap City Easter circus report", holo. signed, 5 pp. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - O'Hara, Frank, "For the Chinese New Year & for Bill Berkson", 2/14/61; ts poem, 3 pp. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - O'Hara, Frank, "Mary Desti's ass", 4/15/61; ts poem, 2 pp. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - O'Hara, Frank, "St. Paul and all that", 5/20/61; ts poem, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Olson, Charles, "In the face of a Chinese view of the city", 1962 Jan 5; ts poem, 2 pp. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Perkoff, Stuart, "The Christian philo", typescript carbon poem, 2 pp. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Perkoff, Stuart, "Three prayers", typescript carbon poem, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Perkoff, Stuart, "The swing", typescript carbon poem, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Rainey, Gertrude, "Sissy blues", ts poem, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Schneemann, C., "About Claes Oldenburg's 'store'", ts, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Schulman, Howard, "Jan Müller (1922-58) at the Guggenheim thru 2/25/62", ts review, 2 pp. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Snyder, Gary, "The curse", ts poem, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Solomon, Norman, "962", ts, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Solomon, Norman, "A passion play. 1", ts, 2 pp. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Sorrentino, Gilbert, "Review of a review (John Fles, Yugen 1-7, KULCHUR 3)", typescript, 2 pp. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Sorrentino, Gilbert, "Prose of our time", annotated typescript, 3 pp. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Sorrentino, Gilbert, "In quest of Ugendun", anno. ts signed, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Spellman, A.B., "A home brew" and "Baltimore oriole", both poems dated 11/60; ts poems, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Stanley, George, "From a letter to Dale Landers", 3/16/61; ts 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Stanley, George, "The Italian", ts poem signed, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Strong, Mike, "After", typescript carbon poem signed, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Strong, Mike, "Mornings", annotated ts poem signed, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Strong, Mike, "Overture", annotated ts poem signed, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Waring, James, letter in answer to Diane Wakoski, annotated typescript, 2 pp. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Waring, James, letter in answer to [Edwin] Denby, 1962 Feb 1; holo. 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Waring, James, untitled poem, 1961 Mar; typescript, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Whalen, Philip, "The art of literature", 1962-63; ts, 19 pp. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Williams, Jonathan, "Best reading list", 1962 Feb; annotated typescript, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Williams, Jonathan, "We take the golden road, to Samar, Kansas...", typescript carbon, 2 pp. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Yu Suwa, "A poem, 1961-1962", holo. poem signed, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Unidentified authors
    - Aquarian, untitled fragment, annotated typescript, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Aquarian, 1/10 of a minyun, "Best reading list.", annotated typescript, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - [ ], John, untitled typescript, including a poem, signed, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - [ ], "All Hallows Eve.", 1968; typescript carbon, 1 p., San Francisco (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - [ ], "Canto.", 1968; typescript carbon, 1 p., San Francisco (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - [ ], "A clinging.", typescript carbon, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - [ ], "Cutting loose.", 1968; typescript carbon, 1 p., San Francisco (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - [ ], "Last gift.", 1968; typescript carbon, 1 p., San Francisco, Halloween. (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Writings
  - Diary, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Notebooks, holo.
    - 1948-19521956-1958 Jan, 7 volumes (Box 4)
    - 1958-1966, 2 volumes (Box 5)
  - Plays
    - Like, 1960; published version (Box 5)
    - Poets Vaudeville
      - Draft A, undated; holo. (Box 5)
      - Draft B, undated; repro. (2 copies) (Box 5)
      - Draft C, 1964; repro. with covers (Box 5)
    - Untitled play, fall and winter 1959; handwritten manuscript (Box 5)
    - Untitled play, autumn 1959; handwritten manuscript (Box 5)
    - Untitled play, fall 1959; handwritten manuscript (Box 5)
  - Readings
    - "The Calculus", undated; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - "The Calculus of Variation" and "Whale Honey", 1963 (Box 5)
    - Selections from The Floating Bear, 1961 (Box 5)
  - Short stories
    - "The Boy Who Made Songs", undated; typescript carbon (Box 5)
  - Translations
    - Untitled from the Latin., undated; mix of handwritten and typed (Box 5)
  - Verse, miscellaneous
    - Typescripts, one signed, 1959; undated (Box 5)
    - Typescript, signed, 1960-1965 (Box 6)
  - Verse, collections
    - Early Poems: 1940-1952, typescript carbon (Box 6)
    - Earthsong: Poems 1957-1959, 1968; typescript with revisions, original and photocopy; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - "Freddie Poems.", 1957-1966; typescript carbon (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1962; typescript, 3 pp. (Box 6)
- Miscellaneous material
  - American Theatre for Poets, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Announcements and leaflets, undated (Box 6)
  - Announcements of poetry readings (Box 6)
  - Copy and layout for Floating Bear #20, incomplete, only one page (Box 6)
  - Copy and miscellaneous items for Floating Bear #26 (Box 6)
  - Notes, handwritten and typed, undated (Box 6)
  - Press release regarding the Floating Bear obscenity case, 1961
Seelcted index to correspondence
Letters are listed alphabetically by sender. An asterisk before a letter's date indicates an accompanying envelope.
Abrams, Sam 1970 Dec n.y. Jan 2
Aldrich, Mike 1969 Sep 10
Allen, Don n.y. Feb 21 * 1961 Sep 5 * 1961 Sep 20 * 1961 Oct 4 * 1961 Oct 20 1961 Oct 30 (postcard) * 1962 Dec 6 (to Rose & Stephen) * 1963 Mar 6 (to Rose & Stephen) 1963 May 22 (postcard, to Rose & Stephen) * 1963 Aug 8
Allen, Samuel * 1969 May 11
Allen, Samuel W. 1969 Aug 26
Anders, Terry Lee 1971 Mar 19 1971 Apr 13 1971 May 19
Ashbery, John n.y. Jan 28 * n.y. Oct 19
Baynard, Ed * 1970 Oct 13
Berenson, Betty & Julia undated (card)
Bergé, Carol 1962 Nov 7 (postcard, to Soren Agenoux, c/o Diane Di Prima)
Berkson, Bill (signed as Minerva Urecal) * 1968 Jun 28 1970 Nov 9 (postcard)
Berman, Wallace * 1968 Jun 13 1968 Dec 17 (postcard, to Diane di Prima & Alan Marlowe)
Bissett, Bill * 1970 Jul * 1970 Jul * 1970 Sep 7 * 1970 Dec 29 * 1971 Feb 2 (short ts note)
Black, Erin 1971 (postcard) * 1971 Mar 22
Borregaard, Angela * 1971 May 23
Boyd, Robert undated (with typescript poem "Jazz & Junkyards Endless Tour" attached)
Brakhage, Jane 1970 Nov 10 (postcard)
Breyer, Chris * 1970 Aug 13
Brilliant, Alan undated (note on an unmailed postcard) * 1970 Aug 21 1970 Nov 4 (postcard) 1970 Nov 29 1970 Dec 15 * 1971 Jan 15 1971 Apr 1 1971 May 5 (on a poetry postcard) * 1971 May 22 * 1971 Jun 3
Buchanon, Ann ca. 1971
Calise, William J. 1962 Nov 26 (carbon, to Charles L. Mee, Jr.)
Campion, Miles (see LeRoi Jones) undated
Claremon, Neil * 1971 May 14
Clements, Marshall 1970 Nov 19
Codrescu, Andrei 1970 Sep 11 1970 Dec 28 (postcard)
Collum, Jack * 1970 Nov 9 * 1970 Dec 10 (attached are two typescript carbon: "Poem for Summer Solstice" and "Signatura Rerum" by Diane di Prima) 1971 Jan 14 * 1971 Mar 16
Cooney Seamus 1970 May 20
Corman, Cid 1963 Jun 15
Creeley, Bob * 1963 Jun 16 (with two-page enclosure)
Creeley [?], Bob 1968 Dec 24 (postcard)
Cruz, Victor Hernandez * 1969 May 24
Currey, Lloyd W. 1969 Aug 2 (postcard)
Dawson, Fielding * 1962 Feb 17 1962 Apr 18 (postcard)
DeLoach, Allen * 1969 Jul 29 * 1970 Aug 12 * 1970 Aug 28 * 1970 Nov 12 * 1970 Dec 18 (on a mimeographed letter of Joan Ford) 1971 Jan 5 (postcard) * 1971 Mar 14
Denby, Edwin undated (to Floating Bear [DDP])
Dine, Jim 1971 Jan 7 (postcard)
DiPrima, Diane undated (to Ol' Bret) undated (postcard, to Jack Collum) undated (to Grant [Fisher]) undated (to "Dearest goon") undated (from "Lucy" to Zen [Alan Marlowe]) undated (to Grant [Fisher]) undated (postcard, to Grant [Fisher]) undated (to Alan [Marlowe]) undated (postcard, to Tim Buckley) undated (to Tom [ ]) undated (to Tom [ ]) n.y. Jan 29 (to Grant [Fisher]) n.y. Jun 16 (photocopy, to Alan [Marlowe]) n.y. Jul 24 (to Judy [ ]) * n.y. Sep 19 (to Allen [Van Newkirk]) 1965 (to Daddy) 1965 Sep 9 (signed Diane di Prima Marlowe, to Mrs. Lester McEachern) 1965 Sep 19 (carbon) (signed Diane di Prima Marlowe, to Arie Hakkert) 1965 Nov 14 (to Larry [ ]) 1966 Jun 6 (to Bob [ ]) 1967 Aug 12 (to Gene LaRue) 1968 May 31 (carbon, to Bill Bissett) (to DiPrima, Diane) 1968 May 31 (carbon) (to Tram Combs Bookstore) 1968 May 31 (carbon) (to Allen de Loach) 1968 May 31 (carbon) (to Panna Grady) 1968 May 31 (carbon) (to Joseph Le Sueur) 1968 May 31 (carbon) (to Josephine Miles) 1968 May 31 (carbon) (to John B. Nomland) 1968 May 31 (carbon) (to Gil Pomeroy) 1968 May 31 (carbon) (to David Wagner) * 1969 Sep 7 (to "Friend Zen") * 1969 Dec 5 (to Alan [Marlowe]) * 1969 Dec 20 (to Alan [Marlowe]) 1970 Jan (to Alan [Marlowe]) 1970 Jan (to Alan [Marlowe]) 1970 Jan (holograph note on a three-page printed text, to [Alan Marlowe]) 1970 Jan 17 (postcard, to Alan Marlowe) * 1970 Mar 8 (to Alan [Marlowe]) * 1970 Mar 12 (to Alan [Marlowe], a note written on a page containing "Poem for Debbie Lee's Birthday") 1970 Jul 11 (to Alan [Marlowe]) 1970 Jul 27 (postcard, to Alan Marlowe) * 1970 Sep (signed "Mini," to Alan [Marlowe]) 1970 Sep 13 (to Alan [Marlowe]) 1970 Dec 7 (postcard #3, to Grant Fisher) 1970 Dec 7 (postcard #4, to Grant Fisher) 1970 Dec 16 (postcard #7, to Grant Fisher) 1970 Dec 16 (postcard #8, from "Di" to Grant Fisher) 1970 Dec 18 (postcard #9, to Grant Fisher) 1971 Jan 25 (postcard, to Grant Fisher) 1971 Jan 25 (postcard, to Grant Fisher) * 1971 Jan 25 (to Grant [Fisher]) 1971 Jan 27 (postcard, to Grant Fisher) 1971 Jan 27 (postcard, to Grant Fisher) * 1971 Feb 2 (to Grant [Fisher]) * 1971 Mar 10 (to Bill Haines, attached is a carbon of William Haines to Dr. Haridas Chaudhuri, 1971 Mar 22) 1970 Jul 22 (to "Grams" [Emma DiPrima]) * 1970 Dec 16 (to "Grams")
DiPrima, Frankie & Weezie * 1971 Apr 14
Doubleday & Co., Anchor Books * 1971 Apr 13
Doyle, Mike undated 1969 Jul 27 1970 Aug 26 1970 Dec 12 * 1971 Jan 5 * 1971 Mar 23 1971 Apr (note)
Durand, Bob * 1971 May 9
Eigner, Larry 1961 Oct 27 (postcard, to LeRoi Jones)
Enslin, Ted * 1971 Jun 3
Evergreen Review see Fred Jordan see Jack Hoffman
Ferlinghetti, Lawrence 1963 Jul 18 (postcard) * 1968 May 22 1970 Dec 25 (postcard)
Follett Publishing Co. see Patricia A. Meehan
Forrister, Frances * 1971 Mar 4 * 1971 May 6 (carbon) (to Moses Soyer) 1971 May 6 (carbon) (to Raphael Soyer)
Fraser, Kathleen 1969 Jul 29
Gadd, Maxine 1969 Jul
Gervais, C.H. undated (postcard) 1971 Jan 21 (postcard)
Ginsberg, Allen * 1968 Oct 13 (to Alan [Marlowe] and Diane [diPrima])
Girodias, Maurice * 1968 Dec 13 * 1969 Oct 29
Gitlin, David * 1971 May 23
Grady, Panna n.y. Jul 12 (postcard) 1970 Aug 23 (postcard) 1970 Oct 11 (postcard) 1971 Jan 7 (postcard) 1971 Apr 4
Griffith, E.V. 1971 Jan 19
Grove Press see Claudia Menza
Guest, Barbara * 1961 Aug 8 * 1961 Sep 25 1971 Jan 15 (postcard)